And what has King William done since he has been in England?
Largely laid waste to it! He has set fire to our forts and buildings,
his armies have trampled over our fields and crops,
burning down our villages and slaughtering their inhabitants.
He has taken land from those who once held it here,
and given it to his barons, so that they might be obedient to him.
In return they must give him knights for an army,
so that his power is strong and we remain weak.
And now,
this survey of theirs will fix our lives forever,
for once these things are set down in it,
they will be given the force of law!
To appeal against them,
there will be no appeal!
For it will be like arguing on the Day of Judgment itself!